A Guide to the Martha Baird Rockefeller papers FA467
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1; 8.36 Cubic Feet 22 letter document boxes
  - Organizations, 1.2
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Rosenkavalier", 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Coq d'Or", 1967 (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Carry-Nation", 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Faust", 1968 (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: MBR Sponsered Productions: "Rigoletto", 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - New York City Opera: "Bomarzo", 1968-1969 (Box 9)
      Clippings; no MBR support.
    - New York Infirmary, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
    - New York Philharmonic: Concert Schedules, 1962-1971 (Box 9)
      MBR's own hand written shedules for NYP and NYCO concerts and programs showing those which she attended; plan of Metropolitan Opera House showing location of MBR's box.
    - New York Philharmonic: Programs and Past Schedules, 1962 October-1964 May (Box 9)
      Schedules for concert seasons and program notes; clippings.
    - New York Philharmonic: Programs and Past Schedules, 1964 October-1968 January (Box 10)
    - New York Philharmonic: Dana S. Creel: Acoustics, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
      MBR pledge to improve acoustics at Philharmonic Hall.
    - New York Philharmonic: Special Opening Gala, 1964 Sept. 29, Mr. Lockwood's Party (Box 10)
      Clippings and program; plans for party.
    - New York Philharmonic: Press, Special, Including Bernstein Composition, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
      Clippings
    - New York Philharmonic: Orchestra, 1952; 1966 (Box 10)
      Invitation to serve on board, declined; contribution for outdoor concert series.
    - New York Philharmonic: Friends of the Philharmonic, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
      Permission to include MBR's name in list of patrons; thanks for contribution.
    - New York Philharmonic: Miscellaneous Art, 1962-1964 (Box 10)
      Clippings on art works at Philharmonic Hall.
    - New York Philharmonic: Miscellaneous, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
      MBR contributions and pledges; outdoor concerts; acoustical problems.
    - Northfield Schools, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      MBR Fund contribution of books and records to school; Mrs. Packard's connection with D. L. Moody.
    - Occidental College: General, 1953-1970 (Box 10)
      Photograph of MBR in 1916; gift in 1962 of $500,000 to be charged against bequest to OC in will dated 1962 June 29.
    - Occidental College: Material for Biographical Alumni Project, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
      MBR Biography.
    - Occidental College: Mr. Wagner and Robert C. Bates, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
      Request by Wagner of OC to include MBR's name in a list of contributors, declined.
    - Olney Street Baptist Church, Providence, 1955 (Box 10)
    - Oriental Institute, University of Chicago, 1960 (Box 10)
      MBR sent colored drawing of wall of Temple of Abydos done by Miss Calverley.
    - Patroness, Sponsorship, Committee, and Board Member Requests, 1954-1955; 1958; 1961-1962 (Box 10)
      Requests to serve, all declined.
    - Planned Parenthood, 1960-1961; 1964; 1966; 1969-1970 (Box 10)
      Annual contributions to PP of Rhode Island.
    - Population Council, 1961-1963; 1965; 1967-1968 (Box 10)
      MBR contribution; JDR 3rd's letters of appeal.
    - Protestant Council of the City of New York, 1961-1963 (Box 10)
      Contribution; proposed memorial to Michael Rockefeller at airport.
    - Providence Atheneum, 1953; 1956 (Box 10)
    - Providence Organizations, 1941-1943; 1948-1951 (Box 10)
      MBR active in Young America; Providence Community Concert Assn.; R. I. Veterans Memorial Auditorium Commision.
    - Public Schools Athletic League, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
    - Redwoods, 1961; 1965; 1967 (Box 10)
      MBR trip to California, 1961, maps, diary, photographs, clippings; Carl Gustafson's memo on problems at Rockefeller Forest.
    - Redwoods: Notes, Mr. Drury's Reports and Correspondence, 1961; 1964; 1966 (Box 10)
      Correspondence with Newton B. Drury, secretary of the Save-the-Redwoods-League; MBR contributions; purchase of timberland.
    - Rhode Island Philharmonic Orchestra., 1952-1961; 1967 (Box 10)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1961 (Box 11)
      Appeals ignored; publication.
    - Riverside Church: Sermons, Programs, Clippings, 1962-1971 (Box 11)
      Transcripts of sermons; church bulletins with MBR's notes and comments.
    - Riverside Church: Dr. Robert J. McCracken, 1964-1969 (Box 11)
      Senior minister; illness, leave of absence; MBR gifts and assistance.
    - Riverside Church: Current (General), 1956; 1958-1960; 1962-1970 (Box 11)
      MBR contribution to general work and radio work of church; MBR contributions to cost of Dr. McCracken's radio series; reports on activity at church, no participation by MBR although she was a member; lists of board members.
    - Riverside Church: Victor Z. Brink, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
      Invitation to meet Dr. Campbell (new minister) delined.
    - Riverside Church: Epsine Sculpture, 1965 (Box 11)
      Discussion of propriety in Protestant church.
    - Riverside Church: Fund for Mrs. McCracken, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Riverside Church: Salute to Dr. & Mrs. Harry Fosdick, 1963 (Box 11)
      MBR remarks at tribute.
    - Riverside Church: Miscellaneous, 1952; 1954; 1956-1959; 1961-1963; 1968 (Box 11)
      Correspondence and clippings.
    - Saratoga Performing Arts Center, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Seal, Dr. Erwin, 1963 (Box 11)
      MBR contribution to Dial-A-Prayer.
    - Silliman University, Philippines, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
      MBR gift for new harpsichord.
    - Sleepy Hollow Country Club, 1960-1962; 1970 (Box 11)
    - Spanish Institute, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - Spaulding Memorial Endowment, 1955 (Box 11)
      Contribution to Albert Spaulding Memorial Endowment.
    - Spelman College, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
      Information of RBF gifts; program; dedication of JDR, Jr. Fine Arts Building.
    - Stetson University, 1960 (Box 11)
      Appeal by J. W. Parrish.
    - Symington, Mrs. Powers (Maude), 1954; 1956; 1961-1963 (Box 11)
      California friend; MBR gift to Schola Cantorum.
    - Turtle Bay Music School, 1955-1956; 1963 (Box 11)
      Contributions
    - Union Church of Pocantico Hills, 1956; 1965-1967 (Box 11)
      MBR correspondence with SCR about Chagall windows; MBR comments on idea; MBR contributions toward cost of windows.
    - Union Theological Seminary, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
      MBR contribution to produce a Christmas opera; later requests declined.
    - United Fund of Rhode Island, 1966; 1969-1970 (Box 11)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1962 (Box 11)
      Appeal declined.
    - Roger Williams General Hospital, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
    - Williamsburg: General, 1951; 1953-1956; 1959-1970 (Box 11)
      Visits; friends; tributes to JDR, Jr.; news of activities; invitations; Carter Grove; board; folk art; Virginia houses; award; maps; MBR pays for Wright copy of Salisbury portrait of JDR, Jr., gift to Virginia; MBR's lifetime pass to exhibition buildings.
    - Williamsburg: Washington's Journal, 1955-1959 (Box 11)
      MBR purchase of Washington's Journal to give to Williamsburg.
    - Williamsburg: Washington Miniatures, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
      MBR gitt of Washington miniatures.
    - Williamsburg: Kenneth Chorley, re: Trumbull Portrait, 1958 (Box 12)
      MBR not interested in buying Trumbull portrait of Washington for Williamsburg
    - Williamsburg: Queen Mother's Visit, 1954 (Box 12)
      Correspondence, itinerary, clippings.
    - Williamsburg: Financing, 1961-1962; 1967 (Box 12)
    - Williamsburg: Visit, 1962 April (Box 12)
      Plans and itinerary for MBR visit.
    - Williamsburg: Local Correspondence, 1946; 1949-1950; 1956; 1958; 1960 (Box 12)
      Letters from Williamsburg residents to and from JDR, Jr.
    - Williamsburg: Board Members, 1955 (Box 12)
      Biographies of directors and trustees.
    - Williamsburg: Bassett Hall Booklet, 1959 (Box 12)
      History of the house.
    - Yosemite, 1963 (Box 12)
    - Young Audiences, 1953; 1958 (Box 12)
  - Baird family, 1.3
    - Arthur M. Allen: Estate & Subsequent Business Matters, 1951-1952 (Box 12)
      Restricted from access - Confidential material.
    - Arthur M. Allen: Death, Prior Medical History, Services, 1949-1952 (Box 12)
    - Arthur M. Allen: Captain John Allen (Box 12)
      Allen family hero in War of 1812; transcript of expliots; photographs.
    - Arthur M. Allen: Correspondence, 1927; 1929; 1939; 1948; 6 pieces. (Box 12)
      personal and legal correspondence.
    - Arthur M. Allen: Photographs of Arthur M. Allen and His Parents (Box 12)
    - Arthur M. Allen: Wright Portraits and Memorial Room at Brown University, 1952 (Box 12)
      MBR gift of portrait of AMA by F. W. Wright to Brown; MBR and JDR, Jr. gift of $100,000 for memorial room and book collection.
    - Arthur M. Allen: Who Was Who Biography, 1954; 1959-1960 (Box 12)
    - Arthur M. Allen: Memberships (Box 12)
      List of clubs, organizations and boards of which AMA was a member; list of names and addresses of employees at AMA's law office, 1949.
    - Marion E. Allen, 1964-1968 (Box 12)
    - Anthony Family Data, 1960-1966 (Box 12)
      Ethel Stien preparing geneology; MBR parents, brother Ralph P. Baird.
    - Baird Estates, 1941; 1955 (Box 12)
      Distribution of estate of George H. Baird, uncle; MBR gave up her share.
    - Baird Family History, 1886-1971 (Box 12)
      Papers of W. F. Baird (father); parent's wedding certificate, 1886; letter to MBR from her father; obituary notices of father, mother and other relatives; letters from Aunt Mary; MBR musical ability at 15.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1951 (Box 12)
      Letters from Josephine P. Baird and Olive Prescot Digges.
    - Mrs. Charles Grey (Ruth), 1956-1970 (Box 12)
      Relative of MBR; personal gifts to pay debts; aid to son.
    - Mrs. Charles Moser (Margaret), 1951-1964 (Box 12)
      Second cousin to MBR, daughter of her father's uncle Thomas Finley of Pennsylvania; Sister to Ruth Finley Grey; MBR sent $5,000 to clear title to farm; other gifts.
    - Mr. and Mrs. James C. Powers, 1951-1966 (Box 12)
      Sister of Arthur Allen; her children; MBR gifts; death; marriages; births.
    - Finley and Various, 1951-1965 (Box 12)
      Annie Finley Jenkins, cousin; Mrs. John F. Finley, cousin; Mr. Robert Finley; Georgina C. Ellis; Susan Cope, cousin; Joseph S. Baird, cousin; Grace M. Baird, widow of cousin; William Finley, cousin, brother of Margaret and Ruth.
  - Martha Baird Rockefeller personal, 1.4
    - Clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 12)
    - Photographs. (Box 12)
      Photos of MBR from 1900 to 1950s; MBR - AMA wedding; MBR's parents, brother and grandparents; "Beecham Cartoon", cartoon by Nerman of MBR and director Sir. Thomas Beecham.
    - Birth Certificate (Box 12)
    - Driving Licence and Driving Test, Berlitz School French Lessons, 1963; 1965; 1968 (Box 12)
    - Divorce Papers, Martha Baird vs. Adrian Van Laar, 1925 (Box 12)
      Papers for divorce, granted in Paris.
    - MBR Handwriting Analysis, Palm Reading, Zodiac, 1928; 1942; 1967 (Box 12)
    - MBR Music - Program Notes, Circulars and Biographies, 1930-1933; 1940 (Box 12)
      Copies of MBR's handouts from her musical career; clippings.
    - Social Security Number, 1962 (Box 12)
      MBR first applied for one in 1962, never had need for one before.
    - Adrian Van Laar, 1952; 1957; 1963; 1969 (Box 12)
      Miscellaneous correspondence concerning MBR first husband.
    - Voting, 1957; 1963; 1969 (Box 12)
      Board of elections voter registration card, 1957, 1969; information on electorial college reform.
    - Who's Who, 1966-1968 (Box 12)
      Appeals by "Who's Who" for biographical information for "Who's Who of American Women", ignored.
  - Possessions, 1.5
    - Antiques (Non-Art), Loan of, 1961-1968 (Box 13)
      Requests to see or borrow antiques, most declined; did send photographs on some occations.
    - Art Works, Request to Borrow or Examine, 1956-1971 (Box 13)
      Requsts to see or borrow art work, most declined; policy on refusing loans of art work.
    - Cars, 1957; 1961-1962; 1964; 1969 (Box 13)
      Cars owned; care of electric; purchases of new cars; sale of used cars.
    - Cookbook, Mrs. Wynne, 1961 (Box 13)
      Acknowledgement.
    - China, 1961-1967 (Box 13)
      Items on consignment, S. P. Conover; Mrs. Duryea sold items for MBR.
    - Chinese Porcelain, 1958-1966; 1970 (Box 13)
      JEL memo on possible gift of porcelain to museum; requests to see porcelains, declined; MBR pleased with Metropolitan display of JDR, Jr. porcelains; visit to museum; color plates (copper ingravings) given to museum.
    - Fur Storage, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
      Receipts for furs put in storage.
    - Jewelry, 1952-1969 (Box 13)
      Sale of some jewelry; possible sale of other pieces; tax problems; safe combination; gift to Edith Tuck; purchase of pearls; emerald necklace; JDR, Jr.'s planning of string of pearls.
    - Parke Bernet, 1961-1965 (Box 13)
      Sale of objects from 740 through Parke Bernet gallery.
    - Pianos, 1955-1959; 1964 (Box 13)
      Purchase of piano for Tucson; gift of Steinway to Association home.
    - Pitt Portrait, 1929-1930; 1946; 1952 (Box 13)
      Authenticity of portrait of William Pitt by John Hoppner owned by MBR and AMA.
    - Racial, undated (Box 13)
      MBR notes on Dr. and Mrs. Boyd who studied racial characterisics.
    - Records, 1963 (Box 13)
      Gift to MBR of Toscanini recordings.
  - Osteopathy, 1.6
    - General, 1960-1969 (Box 13)
      Comments on osteopathy by NAR; MBR contributions; new hospital in Massachusetts.
    - Dr. Hoag's Book, 1961-1969 (Box 13)
      MBR financed writing of book through N. Y. Academy of Osteopathy.
    - Kirksville College of Osteopathy and Surgery, 1960-1970 (Box 13)
      MBR declines to permanently endow professorship at Kirksville; MBR and RBF gifts, preparation, discussion, announcement.
    - Osteopathic Hospital, Massachusetts, 1952-1953; 1962; 1965 (Box 13)
    - Osteopathic Hospital, New York, 1957; 1961-1962 (Box 13)
    - Dr. Perrin T. Wilsen, 1960-1970 (Box 13)
  - Medicine, 1.7
    - Dr. Paul Holbrook, 1960 (Box 14)
      MBR contribution to medical centers in Tucson; payment by JDR, Jr. estate
    - Phelps Memorial Hospital, 1960 (Box 14)
    - Rhode Island Association for Mental Health, 1958 (Box 14)
    - Rhode Island Hospitals, 1953-1955; 1964; 1967-1968 (Box 14)
    - Newport Naval Hospital, 1951 (Box 14)
      MBR gift of spinet piano to hospital.
  - Giving Program, 1.8
    - Dana S. Creel, 1963-1971 (Box 14)
      MBR giving program through office; recommendations; MBR's decisions; notes on conversations; analysis of giving program for 1971-1974; MBR's comments on program; ideas on Julliard; personal assistance for Roland Hayes and Valentine Bangart; pledges to Opera Assn. of New Mexico, Brown University, Metropolitan Opera.
    - Contributions for 1966-1969 and Suggested Contributions for 1968-1970 (Box 14)
      Prepared lists of recipients and amounts.
  - Homes, 1.9
    - Greenrock: General, 1960-1969 (Box 14)
      Budget; division of expenses; guest maps and directions to Pocantico Hills
    - Greenrock: Insurance, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
      MBR personal insurance policy program; cars; workman's compensation; others
    - Greenrock: Mr. Lockwood, 1968 (Box 14)
      Map of Hillcrest; MBR decision not to buy additional property in Pocantico Hills.
    - Greenrock: Mr. Sleinkofer, 1955-1966 (Box 14)
    - Greenrock: Statements, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Greenrock: Tarrytown and Kykuit, 1956-1970 (Box 14)
      Notes, clippings, scraps.
    - Greenrock: Personnel, Organization & Officers, 1967-1969 (Box 14)
    - Greenrock: Superintendant - Kykuit, 1960-1961; 1965; 1968. (Box 14)
    - Hillcrest: Design and Construction - Mott B. Schmidt, 1961-1970; 1977 (Box 14)
      Architect; fees; agreement with uilder and architect; payment for services; problems; changes in construction; discussion of fees; his death.
    - Hillcrest: Purchase of Collier Estate, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
      MBR buys land for Hillcrest from Hills Realty; first refusal to Hills if sold or given to other than descendant of JDR, Jr.
    - Hillcrest: Frances Douglass - Dining Room Wallpaper, 1954-1965 (Box 14)
      MBR gift to Mrs. E. L. Douglass of $2,000 in 1962; antique wallpaper deteriorating, restoration work.
    - Hillcrest: Local Letters and Furniture Lists, 1961-1968 (Box 14)
      Gold key; employment application, offer of rugs and wood panels.
    - Hillcrest: Willard Downing, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
      MBR plans for house.
    - Hillcrest: Garden. (Box 14)
      Shrubs and trees suitable; ones used.
    - Hillcrest: Landscaping, 1964-1968 (Box 14)
      Plans for work by Rosedale Nurseries.
    - Hillcrest: Publicity, Clippings, 1962 (Box 14)
      Release on type and size of house; Hillcrest announcement in Tarrytown Daily News.
    - Hillcrest: Prints, 1962 (Box 14)
      Exterior renderings sent to Mr. Kendrew.
    - Hillcrest: Wylock Lease, 1963 (Box 14)
      Small area leased to Raymond Wylock for yard.
    - Hillcrest: Mrs. Hane, 1964-1970 (Box 14)
    - Kykuit: General, 1958-1963 (Box 14)
    - Kykuit: Japanese Garden, 1961 (Box 14)
      MBR shares in cost of constructing garden.
    - Kykuit: Roof and Terrace Repairs, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
      Arrangements to seal roof; paid for by NAR and Greenrock.
    - Removal of Organ, Jo Davidson's Comments on JDR, Sr. Bust., 1961-1963 (Box 15)
      Taking out organ; Jo Davidson's comments on JDR turned over to NAR.
    - Seal Harbor: General, 1956-1967 (Box 15)
      local correspondence; employee gifts.
    - Seal Harbor: Social Engagements and Clubs, 1951-1965 (Box 15)
      Social engagement calendar for summers of 1951-1959; club memberships.
    - Seal Harbor: Garden, Post Cards, Miscellaneous, 1950; 1953; 1956; 1960; 1969 (Box 15)
      Post card views of Mt. Desert Island, Eyrie; maps, photographs and brouchures for AAR garden.
    - Seal Harbor: Asti-Kim Corporation, 1964-1970 (Box 15)
      Hotel resort at Seal Harbor; MBR purchases stock; Mt. Desert Fund; minutes of meetings.
    - Seal Harbor: Asti-Kim Hotel, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
      Notices of hotel operation.
    - Seal Harbor: Asticou Terraces, 1966; 1970 (Box 15)
      MBR contribution toward cost of Japanese gardens.
    - Seal Harbor: Estate Matters, 1960-1963 (Box 15)
      Sale of MBR property to Hills Realty.
    - Seal Harbor: Fire Damage, 1961-1962 (Box 15)
      MBR payments to clear fire damage in national park area.
    - Seal Harbor: MBR Stocks, 1966-1970 (Box 15)
      Acadia Corporation; Seal Harbor Water Co.; Asti-Kim Corporation; proxies; sale of Water Co.; disposal of Asti-Kim stock.
    - Seal Harbor: Charles Savage, 1959-1964 (Box 15)
      His objections to changes being made in Maine; his plans and programs; loan made by JDR, Jr.; plans to visit Seal Harbor; continuing JDR, Jr. program.
    - 740 Park Avenue: Employees, Retirements, 1952; 1954-1955; 1958-1962; 1964; 1967-1970 (Box 15)
    - 740 Park Avenue: Gifts to Employees - Special & Annual, 1959-1962; 1966-1970 (Box 15)
    - 740 Park Avenue: Household - Current, 1963; 1966; 1968-1970 (Box 15)
    - 740 Park Avenue: Household - Mrs. Packard, 1954-1959; 1961-1970 (Box 15)
    - 740 Park Avenue: Household - Note of Thanks from Employees, 1959-1962; 1964-1970 (Box 15)
    - 740 Park Avenue: Typewriters, 1964 (Box 15)
      Purchase of 2 Remington typewriters.
    - 740 Park Corporation: E. M. Bronfman, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
      Tennant on floor above MBR; decorating their apartment; problems.
    - 740 Park Corporation: Building Cleaning, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
      Cleaning exterior limestone.
    - 740 Park Corporation: Directives, Notices, 1963-1970 (Box 16)
      Tenants; security; memberships.
    - 740 Park Corporation: Furniture for Lobby, 1964-1965 (Box 16)
      Purchase.
    - 740 Park Corporation: George Leib, 1963 (Box 16)
      Informal meetings on care of building.
    - 740 Park Corporation: Lease, 1960 (Box 16)
      Transfer to MBR.
    - 740 Park Corporation: Monthly Statements from Agency, 1967-1970 (Box 16)
    - Providence: House, 1930; 1933; 1951; 1962; 1963; 1966 (Box 16)
      AMA - MBR house; photographs of interior; correspondence with new owners.
    - JY Ranch, 1953-1955 (Box 16)
      Gifts to employees; enjoyment of ranch.
  - Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, 1.10
    - Current, 1965-1970 (Box 16)
      Activity of Fund; informal reports from Mr. Engel; appeals to Fund, MBR comments.
    - Auditions, 1961-1967 (Box 16)
      Tour of Europe; listening to performers; Engel's reports.
    - Carter, Elliot and Michael Colgrass, 1966-1967 (Box 16)
      Activities of 2 MF grant recipients; clippings.
    - Engel, Donald, 1958-1969 (Box 16)
      Director of MF; comments on Fund programs; salary.
    - Financial Reports, Salaries, 1966-1969 (Box 16)
      Salary increases for staff; statements of expenses.
    - Incorporation, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
      Planning for incorporation; proposals; discussions; final allocations; tax exempt status.
    - Maynor, Dorothy, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
      MBR purchases piano for St. James School of the Arts.
    - Music Fund Meetings, 1962-1965 (Box 16)
      Dockets and minutes; MBR notes.
    - Music Fund Meetings, 1966-1971 (Box 17)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Young Artists Series, 1956-1968 (Box 17)
      MBR and Fund finance young artists concert series at museum.
    - Miscellaneous Memos, 1956; 1959-1961 (Box 17)
      Re. operations of Fund; clippings.
    - Moore, Douglas, 1956; 1961; 1963; 1966; 1968-1969 (Box 17)
      Member of MF Board; resignation; death; clippings.
    - Mosely, Carlos, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
      Election to Board of Trustees.
    - Osborne, Conrad, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Personal Notes, 1964-1966 (Box 17)
    - Prospects, 1958-1964 (Box 17)
    - Purposes, 1955-1959 (Box 17)
      Original purposes, 1955; revision, 1959.
    - 7 Year Report, 1962-1969. 1969-1970 (Box 17)
    - Schnabel Records Project, 1958-1966 (Box 17)
      Lists of schools receiving sets of Schnabel records from Fund; MBR's wish to preserve Schnabel's contribution; publication of Schnabel's composition; thanks.
    - Schnabel Memorial Committee, 1951-1959 (Box 17)
      Cesar Saerchinger book on Schnabel; MBR contribution to cost; MBR read manuscript and made suggestions.
  - Rockefeller family philanthropy, 1.11
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Rockefeller University, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1960-1965 (Box 17)
      RF: Wright Patman inquiry re MBR offices in non-profit organizations, RBF, NEC; RU: History of Rockefeller Institute. RBF: MBR elected to board, 1960.
    - Rockefeller Family Fund: Meeting Agendas and Dockets, 1968-1970 (Box 18)
      For meetings of 6/4/68; 2/13/69; 6/3/69; 2/4/70.
    - Rockefeller Family Fund, 1967-1970 (Box 18)
      Creation and purpose; bylaws; minutes of meetings.
    - Rockefeller Family & Associates, 1965-1969 (Box 18)
      Minutes of meetings, 1965-1969; matching gifts, MBR participation in educational matching program run through New York office; MBR participation in New York office costs, office management committee meetings; gifts made to individuals through office.
  - Rockefeller family correspondence, 1.12
    - Aldrich, 1953-1967 (Box 18)
      Lucy T. Aldrich to MBR; visits; Harriet Aldrich to MBR; death of William T. Aldrich; Alexander Aldrich; thanks for political contribution.
    - Carmichael, Bessie de Cuevas, 1960 (Box 18)
      MBR sends belated wedding present.
    - Chistmas Gift Lists, 1960; 1963-1968 (Box 18)
    - Christmas Office Party, Name Card, 1966 (Box 18)
    - de Cuevas, George and Margaret, 1957-1965 (Box 18)
      MBR refuses to aid ballet; his death.
    - Rockefeller family Clippings, 1957-1958; 1964-1965 (Box 18)